<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <TipSetDef>
    <defName>SoSGameplayTips</defName>
    <tips>
      <!-- Quests -->
      <li TKey="SoSTipScan">Once in orbit, colonists can scan at a ship's science console to discover orbital quest sites. Send colonists in a shuttle to visit them.</li>
      <li TKey="SosTipAICore">Once in orbit, advanced sensors will automatically scan for orbital quest sites. Multiple cores can speed this process along.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipAsteroids">Asteroids are a great source of building materials in space, but beware of what may lurk inside...</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipDebris">The skies of most rimworlds are filled with orbital debris. Some may even contain survivors of the ship's crew, now crazed and cannibalistic.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSatellites">Clever starship captains can hijack ancient satellites to control weather or bombard their foes. This risks triggering mechanoid-based defenses, however...</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipJTDrive">Johnson-Tanaka drives are typically only found on the largest ships, such as interstellar passenger liners.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSpaceBugs">Ages ago, genetic engineers created colonies of vacuum-adapted insects intended to mine asteroids. This was not a good idea.</li>

      <!-- Combat -->
      <li TKey="SoSTipNoWeapons">An unarmed ship is easy prey. Install weapons before launching, or bring a shuttle and a competent boarding party.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipHeatsinks">Heatsinks are critical to a ship's performance in combat. More heat capacity means your shields will stay up longer.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipRadiators">A ship can't radiate heat while its cloaking device is active. Make sure to disable it once your ship becomes dangerously hot.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipBoardingParties">Enemy ships will launch boarding parties once their weapons have broken your hull. You can use point defense capable ship weapons to help repel boarders.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipBoardingParties2">Many ships are vulnerable to a skilled boarding party. You can send shuttles over to the enemy ship but beware their point-defense weapons. While the enemy ship has working engines only small shuttles can reach it.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipHackBridge">A colonist can use the Intellectual skill to hack an enemy ship's bridge, placing it under your control. Some captains weld multiple captured ships together.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipDetach">Pieces of a ship separated from its bridge will detach and drift away. They are unrecoverable so if you want to obtain most of the resources target enemy ship's consoles and AI cores or use a boarding party.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipRange">Ship railguns are best at long range. Plasma weapons can be used at medium range or closer. Lasers are only effective up close.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipTorpedo">A well-placed torpedo can overload shields and shatter hull, assuming it isn't intercepted by point-defense weaponry.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSpinal">Spinal-mount cannons deal more damage, and produce larger explosions, the more amplifiers they contain.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipEngines">Larger ships require more engines to move quickly in combat. Often a small, nimble ship can outrun a heavily-armed opponent.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSalvage">Each salvage bay can move up to 5000 units of ship weight. Build multiple bays to efficiently move larger wrecks.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipAbandon">When your ship is defeated in combat, any crew inside spacer cryptosleep caskets or spacer cribs will land somewhere on the planet below. There, your story can begin anew.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipAirlocks">When boarding an enemy ship, its airlocks can be breached with the Construction skill or hacked with the Intellectual skill.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipCombatPower">The more combat-capable your ship is, the more likely you are to be challenged by formidable enemies.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipEmergencyPurge">An emergency purge port can eject molten silver into space, quickly reducing a ship's stored heat - albeit at a fantastic cost.</li>

      <!-- Shuttles -->
      <li TKey="SoSTipShuttles">Shuttlecraft come in four sizes. Only the smallest among them is powered by chemfuel; larger cargo shuttles require nuclear fuel.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipShuttleBay">Shuttle bays allow cargo and passengers to enter a ship without ever risking vacuum exposure.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipFullyFueled">A shuttle must be fully fueled to travel to or from orbit. When traveling between ground sites, they are slightly less fuel-efficient than transport pods.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipHoverMode">Shuttlecraft can be placed in "hover mode" to act as pack animals for caravans. They will consume fuel slowly in this mode.</li>

      <!-- Misc ship stuff -->
      <li TKey="SoSTipVacuum">Vacuum exposure is not fun. Be sure to have EVA suits on hand in case of a hull breach.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipLifeSupport">A ship only needs one life support system, but having a backup can save your crew in an emergency.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipInterstellar">To travel between planets, you'll need a Johnson-Tanaka drive, a ship computer core, and lots of stored energy.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipReactor">Ship reactors can be overdriven, increasing their power output at the risk of fire and radiation exposure.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipCapacitor">Ship capacitors contain an integrated fuse system, preventing short-circuit events.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipHydroponics">Thanks to hydroponics and artificial soil substrates, it is possible to build a fully self-sustaining colony in orbit.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipMood">Most colonists are excited to go to space, and even more so when on EVA. Wimps and undergrounders, however, will be terrified.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSensors">Ship sensors and science consoles can remotely observe some maps, allowing you to plan attacks in advance or scout landing sites.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipLanding">In order to land, ships require an area that supports heavy construction, is free of buildings and not under a mountain.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipTradeShips">Occasionally you will encounter trade ships in orbit. You can attempt to pirate them, but expect bounty hunters to pursue you as your notoriety rises.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipResources">Useful resources are surprisingly abundant in space. You might want to launch a small ship at first, then gradually expand it.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipCrittersleep">Crittersleep caskets can store many small animals, such as cats or puppies. You will need to anesthetize them first.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipFloors">Floors can be built atop ship hull tile. Your gold-paneled bridge will be the envy of every lesser captain.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipHolodeck">The holodeck can train any skill, depending on the program your colonist selects when using it. More advanced holodecks train skills faster.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipCloak">The cloaking device prevents enemy ships from noticing you. It is useless once combat has already begun, however.</li>
	  <li TKey="SoSFormgel">A modern replacement for antiquated hologram technology, formgels are swarms of mechanites which mimic biological human bodies.</li>

      <!-- Archotech -->
      <li TKey="SoSTipArchotechSpore">Spacer legends tell of archotech spores - ship computer cores that have begun upgrading themselves into archotechs. Usually this requires mental contact with an existing archotech...</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSporeMood">Archotech spores are temperamental beings, and will play "pranks" on their crew if their mood dips too low.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSporeSacrifice">You can improve an archotech spore's mood by having colonists meditate nearby, or by giving it the brain of a prisoner to examine. This kills the prisoner.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipSporeGifts">An archotech spore will sometimes offer its human progenitors gifts. The more technologies it has unlocked, the more gifts are available.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipPillars">In order to quickly evolve into a full archotech, an archotech spore can reverse-engineer artifacts known as Pillars. Four are known to exist on the Rim, all well-guarded.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipEndgame">No lesser being can stand against an archotech. Once your archotech spore completes its evolution, the world will be yours.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipPsychicField">Once the appropriate research has been completed, an archotech spore can generate a wide range of psychic phenomena upon request.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipArcholife">"Archolife" creatures were designed by an archotech spore. They resemble mundane animals but do not need to eat, are effectively immortal, and even generate a shield in combat.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipFlayer">The Psychic Flayer is a dreaded weapon employed by the most advanced starships. It can stun dozens of crew at once, allowing boarding parties to do their work unopposed.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipMechanites">Shipeater mechanites can consume almost any solid material, but will be disabled by firefoam or water.</li>
      <li TKey="SoSTipRecyclotron">Invented by an archotech spore, the Recyclotron is capable of taking apart nearly any object at 100% efficiency.</li>

      <li TKey="EclecticIsBestCat">The archocat was designed in the image of "Eclectic" and "Hitomi" - two early 21st-century housepets universally regarded as history's most lovable cats.</li>
    </tips>
  </TipSetDef>
  
</Defs>
