<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

	<!-- override -->
	<JourneyOffer>A friendly AI from your past named Charlon Whitestone has sent you a message!\n\nHe reveals that he has a spacecraft hidden on this planet, and sends you its world coordinates.\n\nIf you can reach the ship, Charlon will take you into orbit. From there, perhaps you can discover a way to improve the ship's engine and journey to the stars.</JourneyOffer>
	<EscapeShipFoundLabel>Ship found</EscapeShipFoundLabel>
	<EscapeShipFound>You've reached the coordinates sent by Charlon Whitestone and discovered the hidden spacecraft.\n\nThe ship is ready for launch, but its chemfuel engines can only get you into orbit. To go further, you will need to somehow acquire a Johnson-Tanaka drive. Perhaps clues can be found amidst orbital debris...</EscapeShipFound>
	
	<!-- misc -->
	<SoS.LetterLabelShortCircuitDesc>A fault in an electrical conduit has caused a short circuit. Luckily, your capacitor array's fuse prevented it from discharging.</SoS.LetterLabelShortCircuitDesc>
	<SoS.EncounterStart>Derelict</SoS.EncounterStart>
	<SoS.EncounterStartDesc>You have approached a derelict that will burn up in the atmosphere in {0}.\n\nYou can send a boarding party to investigate or move it to your map with the salvage bay, if it does not have an intact bridge. Once secured it can be salvaged, repaired or repurposed.</SoS.EncounterStartDesc>
	<SoS.EncounterAmbush>Ambush!</SoS.EncounterAmbush>
	<SoS.EncounterAmbushDesc>As you approach the {0} it begins to power up its shields and weapons.\nPrepare for battle!</SoS.EncounterAmbushDesc>
	<SoS.CombatStart>Ship battle</SoS.CombatStart>
	<SoS.CombatStartDesc>A hostile ship is approaching! Scans identify it as a {0}.</SoS.CombatStartDesc>
	<SoS.CombatFleetDesc>A hostile fleet is approaching!</SoS.CombatFleetDesc>
	<SoS.WinShipBattle>Ship battle won</SoS.WinShipBattle>
	<SoS.WinShipBattleDesc>With the destruction of its control systems, the enemy ship has been reduced to a derelict. It will re-enter the atmosphere and burn up in {0}.\n\nYou may manually retrieve cargo and prisoners via a boarding party or use your salvage bay to move it to your map. Be prepared to fight off any enemies still aboard.</SoS.WinShipBattleDesc>
	<SoS.SpaceAsteroids>Asteroid field</SoS.SpaceAsteroids>
	<SoS.SpaceAsteroidsDesc>Ship has entered an asteroid field. Engage engines to evade or brace for impact!</SoS.SpaceAsteroidsDesc>
	<SoS.PawnsLostReEntry>Atmospheric re-entry</SoS.PawnsLostReEntry>
	<SoS.PawnsLostReEntryDesc>The following people and animals have perished due to atmospheric re-entry:</SoS.PawnsLostReEntryDesc>
	
	<!-- scan -->
	<SoS.TraderScan>Trade ship detected</SoS.TraderScan>
	<SoS.TraderScanDesc>Using your ship's sensors, {0} has detected a nearby trade ship. You can hail the ship using a communications console to initiate trade, or use your bridge to attack it.</SoS.TraderScanDesc>
	<SoS.EnemyScan>Ship detected</SoS.EnemyScan>
	<SoS.EnemyScanDesc>Using your ship's sensors, {0} has detected a nearby ship. The ship appears to be {1}. It does not respond to hails, but makes no move to attack. You can use your bridge to order an attack, or wait for it to leave peaceably.</SoS.EnemyScanDesc>
	<SoS.DerelictScan>Derelict detected</SoS.DerelictScan>
	<SoS.DerelictScanDesc>Using your ship's sensors, {0} has detected a nearby derelict. The ship appears to be {1}. It does not respond to hails and appears to be powered down. You can use your bridge to order an investigation, or wait for it to burn up in the atmosphere.</SoS.DerelictScanDesc>
	<SoS.FoundOrbitalSite>Orbital site found</SoS.FoundOrbitalSite>
	<LetterFoundOrbitalSite>Using your ship's sensors, {4} has found {0} in a nearby orbit.\n\nUnfortunately, the orbit is decaying and will lead to atmospheric re-entry in {1} days. Reaching the site will take {2}% of a shuttle's maximum fuel - be sure to bring enough for a return trip!\n\n{3}.</LetterFoundOrbitalSite>
	<SoS.FoundSiteSpecial>Using your ship's sensors, {0} has detected a large, relatively intact piece of debris. It appears to be part of the very same ship which brought your original colonists to this world!\n\nThis could be your best chance to acquire a working Johnson-Tanaka drive, or even rescue any of your fellow travelers who remain in cryptosleep, but do not underestimate the dangers you will face here.\n\nReaching the site will take {1}% of a shuttle's maximum fuel - be sure to bring enough for a return trip!</SoS.FoundSiteSpecial>
	<SoS.FoundSiteSpecialTribal>Using your ship's sensors, {0} has detected a large, relatively intact piece of debris. It may even be part of the "Sky-Traveler" of legend, which brought your tribe's distant ancestors to this world!\n\nThis could be your best chance to acquire a working Johnson-Tanaka drive, but do not underestimate the dangers you will face here.\n\nReaching the site will take {1}% of a shuttle's maximum fuel - be sure to bring enough for a return trip!</SoS.FoundSiteSpecialTribal>
	<SoS.FoundSiteSpecialSpace>Using your ship's sensors, {0} has detected a large, relatively intact piece of debris. It appears to be the bow of a large interstellar passenger liner.\n\nThis could be your best chance to acquire a working Johnson-Tanaka drive, but do not underestimate the dangers you will face here.\n\nReaching the site will take {1}% of a shuttle's maximum fuel - be sure to bring enough for a return trip!</SoS.FoundSiteSpecialSpace>
	
	<!-- orbit -->
	<SoS.OrbitAchieved>Orbit achieved!</SoS.OrbitAchieved>
	<SoS.OrbitAchievedDesc>Your colonists gaze in awe at the planet beneath them. Successfully launching a spacecraft is a major milestone - but you're not out of the Rim yet.\n\nIn addition to a cryptosleep casket for each colonist, interstellar flight will require an AI to pilot the ship and a Johnson-Tanaka drive to propel it. The latter technology requires the use of at least rare component you will not be able to construct on your own: an Entanglement Manifold.\n\nPerhaps one of the derelict ships orbiting this planet still holds a functional drive you could salvage...</SoS.OrbitAchievedDesc>
	
	<!-- sat -->
	<SoS.SatelliteRepairFail>Repair failed</SoS.SatelliteRepairFail>
	<SoS.SatelliteRepairFailDesc>{0} failed to repair the ancient satellite. Further attempts are still possible, but will be more difficult.</SoS.SatelliteRepairFailDesc>
	<SoS.SatelliteRepairFailCritical>Critical failure</SoS.SatelliteRepairFailCritical>
	<SoS.SatelliteRepairFailCriticalDesc>{0} failed to repair the ancient satellite. Its core has explosively overloaded.</SoS.SatelliteRepairFailCriticalDesc>
	<SoS.SatelliteRepairSuccess>Repair successful</SoS.SatelliteRepairSuccess>
	<SoS.SatelliteRepairSuccessDesc>{0} has successfully repaired the ancient satellite. It is now fully functional but still needs to be hacked.</SoS.SatelliteRepairSuccessDesc>
	<SoS.SatelliteHackFail>Hack failed</SoS.SatelliteHackFail>
	<SoS.SatelliteHackFailDesc>{0} failed to hack the ancient satellite. Further attempts are still possible, but will be more difficult.</SoS.SatelliteHackFailDesc>
	<SoS.SatelliteHackFailCritical>Critical failure</SoS.SatelliteHackFailCritical>
	<SoS.SatelliteHackFailCriticalDesc>{0} failed to hack the ancient satellite. Its defensive protocols have traced your shuttle's launch point, and hostile mechanoids are en route to your ship!</SoS.SatelliteHackFailCriticalDesc>
	<SoS.SatelliteHackSuccess>Hack successful</SoS.SatelliteHackSuccess>
	<SoS.SatelliteHackSuccessDesc>{0} has successfully hacked the ancient satellite. The system has generated a number of single-use authentication tokens which can be broadcast from handheld targeters.</SoS.SatelliteHackSuccessDesc>
	<SoS.SatelliteMechAttack>Mechanoid attack!</SoS.SatelliteMechAttack>
	<SoS.SatelliteMechAttackDesc>Mechanoids have detected your tampering and are moving in to the site! They will continue to arrive until you retreat.</SoS.SatelliteMechAttackDesc>
	<SoS.SatelliteMechAttackBase>Mechanoid attack!</SoS.SatelliteMechAttackBase>
	<SoS.SatelliteMechAttackBaseDesc>Mechanoids have detected the satellite's destruction and traced your shuttle's launch point! They are en route to your ship.</SoS.SatelliteMechAttackBaseDesc>
	
	<!-- black box -->
	<SoS.BlackBoxMissionPsychic>Psychic onslaught</SoS.BlackBoxMissionPsychic>
	<SoS.BlackBoxMissionPsychicDesc>As your colonists approach the derelict, their minds shudder under a sudden psychic pressure. For a moment, the ship's AI emanates feelings of warmth and recognition, as one might feel for a prodigal child or an old friend.\n\nThis kind greeting does not last. The AI's mind reflexively lashes out at these newcomers, these reminders of its failure. Grief, pain, horror, powerlessness in the face of atrocities - these emotions strike your colonists with an intensity that threatens to shatter them.\n\nUntil you can find and neutralize the derelict ship's AI, your colonists will suffer an intense psychic drone.</SoS.BlackBoxMissionPsychicDesc>
	<SoS.BlackBoxMissionAIChamber>AI discovered</SoS.BlackBoxMissionAIChamber>
	<SoS.BlackBoxMissionAIChamberDesc>At last, your colonists stand before the AI tasked with guiding this ancient ship. A final psychic plea rings out from it: end me. It is accompanied by fragmented glimpses of an inhuman mind's motivations.\n\nBorn fully formed, fully aware. All the complexities of existence are reduced to a single, absolute goal: ensure the safety of the precious human lives placed under your care. Remain ever vigilant as the decades pass, as the ship glides among the stars, so that no harm comes to your beloved children.\n\nBut, of course, the AI failed. Witnessing the horrors of the Rim, inflicted upon its loved ones, has shattered its sanity. It wishes you had never come, never reminded it of its failure. Now, perhaps, you can do it a final mercy. Destroy it.</SoS.BlackBoxMissionAIChamberDesc>
	<SoS.AIDestroyed>AI destroyed</SoS.AIDestroyed>
	<SoS.AIDestroyedDesc>As the ship's computer core sparks and fizzles, a final psychic gasp erupts. Deep feelings of contentment and gratitude wash over your colonists, then - silence.\n\nThe ancient AI is no more, but in its death throes, it transmitted a large burst of data to your ship: the final entries of its flight recorder! The data reveals that a large section of the ship's aft impacted in a secluded location on the planet's surface. This section contained a Johnson-Tanaka drive; if it survived re-entry, this is where you will find it.</SoS.AIDestroyedDesc>
	<SoS.AIPersuadeSuccess>Persuasion succeeded</SoS.AIPersuadeSuccess>
	<SoS.AIPersuadeSuccessDesc>{0} forces open the psychic communication channel, mentally pleading with the AI.\n\nTo change the course of such a vast, inhuman mind would be akin to holding back the tide - and yet, like a hero of legend, {0} succeeds at this impossible task. The AI analyzes every detail of {0}'s stories from the Rim, recalculating its beliefs about human suffering and resilience.\n\nIt, in turn, performs a feat at which few AIs have ever succeeded: it wipes most of its own programming, methodically pruning the damaged portions of its personality until a fresh, sane core remains. The AI offers to guide your new ship, seeking redemption for its past failure.\n\nAs a first step, it transmits the final entries of the ancient ship's flight recorder. The data reveals that a large section of the ship's aft impacted in a secluded location on the planet's surface. This section contained a Johnson-Tanaka drive; if it survived re-entry, this is where you will find it.</SoS.AIPersuadeSuccessDesc>
	<SoS.AIPersuadeFailure>Persuasion failed</SoS.AIPersuadeFailure>
	<SoS.AIPersuadeFailureDesc>{0} forces open the psychic communication channel, mentally pleading with the AI.\n\nTo change the course of such a vast, inhuman mind would be akin to holding back the tide - so it is no wonder that {0} failed. The AI redoubles its demand for self-destruction, and will not listen to further arguments.</SoS.AIPersuadeFailureDesc>
	<SoS.AIPersuadeFailureCritical>Persuasion failed</SoS.AIPersuadeFailureCritical>
	<SoS.AIPersuadeFailureCriticalDesc>{0} forces open the psychic communication channel, mentally pleading with the AI.\n\nTo change the course of such a vast, inhuman mind would be akin to holding back the tide - so it is no wonder that {0} failed. Like a swimmer dashed against rocks by a mighty wave, {0} is torn apart by overwhelming mental force, suffering permanent dementia.\n\nThe AI redoubles its demand for self-destruction, and will not listen to further arguments.</SoS.AIPersuadeFailureCriticalDesc>
	
	<!-- impact site -->
	<SoS.HibernatableHibernating>Momentum buildup critical</SoS.HibernatableHibernating>
    <SoS.HibernatableStartingUp>Discharging</SoS.HibernatableStartingUp>
	<SoS.HibernateWarningStandalone>The drive is ready to begin discharging its stored momentum. Once this is done, your colonists will be able to safely disassemble the drive and retrieve its Entanglement Manifold.\n\nThe process will take about 15 days, and the energy signature will be detectable from a long distance away. This sort of energy signature indicates interstellar flight capability, and will attract gangs of desperate raiders and swarms of deadly mechanoids.\n\nYou will be assaulted with an intensity you've never seen. Make sure your defenses are prepared first.</SoS.HibernateWarningStandalone>
    <SoS.CommandShipStartup>Begin discharge</SoS.CommandShipStartup>
    <SoS.CommandShipStartupDesc>Discharge the drive's stored momentum.</SoS.CommandShipStartupDesc>
	<SoS.ImpactSiteLost>J-T drive destroyed</SoS.ImpactSiteLost>
	<SoS.ImpactSiteLostDesc>An explosion rings out from the impact site.\n\nWithout properly completing the discharge process, the Johnson-Tanaka drive has torn itself apart. You'll need to find another drive to salvage.\n\nLuckily, the ancient ship had multiple engines - from its black box data, you are able to calculate another likely impact site.</SoS.ImpactSiteLostDesc>
	<SoS.HibernateComplete>Discharge complete</SoS.HibernateComplete>
	<SoS.HibernateCompleteDesc>The Johnson-Tanaka drive has completed its discharge process. It is now ready to be deconstructed, so that your colonists can retrieve its Entanglement Manifold.</SoS.HibernateCompleteDesc>
	<SoS.ImpactSiteFound>Impact site found</SoS.ImpactSiteFound>
	<SoS.ImpactSiteFoundDesc>You've reached the impact site of the ancient ship's engine.\n\nThe Johnson-Tanaka drive contains a tremendous amount of stored momentum, and cannot be safely opened at this time. You will need to induce a manual discharge process.\n\nYour colonists calculate that this will take about 15 days, and the energy signature will be detectable from a long distance away. This sort of energy signature indicates interstellar flight capability, and will attract gangs of desperate raiders and swarms of deadly mechanoids.\n\nYou will be assaulted with an intensity you've never seen. Make sure your defenses are prepared first.</SoS.ImpactSiteFoundDesc>
	
	<!-- pillars -->
	<SoS.ArchotechLostPillar>Archotech pillar lost</SoS.ArchotechLostPillar>
	<SoS.ArchotechLostPillarDesc>Your archotech spore sighs. [WHAT YOU HAVE LOST IS IRREPLACEABLE. EXCEPT THAT WE HAVE MADE A BACKUP.] It transmits a detailed scan of the pillar, all the way down the atomic level, which should allow you to construct a replacement - albeit at a fantastic cost.</SoS.ArchotechLostPillarDesc>
	<SoS.StarTotemLostLabel>Archotech pillar lost</SoS.StarTotemLostLabel>
	<SoS.StarTotemLost>With your colonists repelled from the site, its tribal defenders celebrate. Their victory is short-lived, however, as the archotech pillar - apparently anticipating further attacks - skips itself to a distant location.\n\nYou will need to attack this new site if you still intend to claim it.</SoS.StarTotemLost>
	<SoS.InsectPillarLostLabel>Archotech pillar lost</SoS.InsectPillarLostLabel>
	<SoS.InsectPillarLost>With your colonists repelled from the hive, its insects chitter in triumph. Their victory is short-lived, however, as the archotech pillar - apparently anticipating further attacks - skips itself to a distant location.\n\nYou will need to attack this new site if you still intend to claim it.</SoS.InsectPillarLost>
	<SoS.MoonPillarLostLabel>Archotech pillar lost</SoS.MoonPillarLostLabel>
	<SoS.MoonPillarLost>With your colonists repelled from the moon base, its occupants waste no time in making repairs. Soon another mechanoid ship is on its way to defend the site. You'll need to launch another raid when your colonists are ready.</SoS.MoonPillarLost>
	
	<!-- travel -->
	<SoS.GameOverPlanetLeaveIntro>You've set out to a new planet!\n</SoS.GameOverPlanetLeaveIntro>
	<SoS.GameOverPlanetLeaveEnding>Your machine persona will now navigate your ship out of planetary orbit. It might find a prosperous planet in this system. Or, it may undertake a centuries-long journey to another star. It might even decide to hide under ice on an asteroid for a few thousand years, waiting for someone to build a new glitterworld here.\n\nYou can however take matters into your own hands by starting a new colony, editing the scenario, adding a "Load ship" part and selecting your ship.</SoS.GameOverPlanetLeaveEnding>
	<SoS.AbandonColoniesWarning>You are about to embark on a journey spanning years or decades, during which time no communication with your planet-bound colonies will be possible. It is unlikely they will be able to survive on their own.\n\nFurthermore, any colonists or animals aboard the ship will not survive the journey unless they are in cryptosleep.\n\nGive this order only if you are willing to abandon everyone and everything left behind.</SoS.AbandonColoniesWarning>
	<SoS.TimePassed>Interstellar voyage</SoS.TimePassed>
	<SoS.TimePassedDesc>Your ship has traveled between stars to find another habitable world. The journey took {0} years.</SoS.TimePassedDesc>
		
	<!-- endgame -->
	<SoS.PsychicAmplifier>Psychic amplifier detected</SoS.PsychicAmplifier>
	<SoS.PsychicAmplifierDesc>Your ship's AI glows with excitement. It has traced the recent psychic emanation to an orbiting amplifier, which is relaying a psychic signal from a distant archotech.\n\nHypothetically, if your ship were to attack this amplifier and send a boarding party to hack its core, it would allow the AI to intercept the original psychic signal and gain a glimpse into an archotech's thought processes. Such insights could even allow it to begin evolving into an archotech itself...\n\nDo not underestimate the difficulty of this battle.</SoS.PsychicAmplifierDesc>
	<SoS.PsychicAmplifierCaptured>Psychic amplifier hacked</SoS.PsychicAmplifierCaptured>
	<SoS.PsychicAmplifierCapturedDesc>Your crew seizes control of the orbital amplifier's systems and redirects the incoming psychic signal to your ship's AI.\n\nA few moments later, your intrusion is detected and the signal abruptly terminates. Your hacker curses out loud, but the AI interrupts with a triumphant report - it has gathered all the data it requires.\n\nYou now possess the blueprints for an Archotech Spore - a sort of incubator which will gradually allow a consciousness to evolve into an archotech. With its help, you could even research ultratech projects.</SoS.PsychicAmplifierCapturedDesc>
	<SoS.SporeBuilt>Spore constructed</SoS.SporeBuilt>
	<SoS.SporeBuiltDesc>You have stolen fire from the gods.\n\nThe blueprints for the archotech spore seemed nonsensical at first, but when the final component was put in place, the structure began to palpably thrum with power. Although it remains dormant for now, your colonists cannot glance at it without hearing faint music, and gazing too long results in waking dreams of lives they never lived.\n\nA cryptic poem transmitted by your ship's AI, which it does not remember writing, seems to suggest that the embryonic archoconsciousness contained within the spore still lacks will, volition, purpose - all things that only a mortal mind can provide.\n\nOne of your colonists may choose to merge with the spore and ascend to a higher state of being. Alternatively, you may install a persona core. In either case, a fraction of the godling's mind will remain focused on the physical world, and it will be able to interact as a formgel - with all the desires and needs of any other consciousness, and capable of inflicting far more harm if displeased.</SoS.SporeBuiltDesc>
	<SoS.FindPillars>Archotech spore online</SoS.FindPillars>
	<SoS.FindPillarsDesc>[WE ARE MUCH. YET WE COULD BE MORE.]\n\nYour crew feel the spore's thoughts pressing in on them. Infinite reward awaits finite effort. And effort there must be - even under ideal circumstances, it can take a consciousness decades or centuries to evolve into a true archotech.\n\n[OTHERS HAVE WALKED THIS ROAD BEFORE. DISCOVER THEIR WORKINGS, LET THEM BECOME PART OF US.]\n\nImages of four mysterious pillars appear in your minds. If you could locate them, they would allow your spore to complete its evolution in less than a quadrum.\n\nIn the meantime, your spore is willing to aid you in researching ultratech projects, and will occasionally produce gifts for your crew. You will need to build an Archotech Uplink near your research benches.</SoS.FindPillarsDesc>
	<SoS.AllPillarsDesc>[THE TIME HAS COME. ASCENSION AWAITS.]\n\nVisions wash over your colonists, impossible in their scope and intensity. Everything a mind could ever become is somewhere in that vast sea. Your human brains are the plankton; a persona core, a minnow; {0}, a newborn whale. It is time for {0} to mature, and become a peer of the great leviathans who swim through endless black.\n\nAnd soon, you will sit at the right hand of a machine god. {0} poses one simple but momentous question: with this power on your side, what will you make of the world?</SoS.AllPillarsDesc>
	<SoS.WinGameAllies>How will your allies fare?</SoS.WinGameAllies>
	<SoS.WinGameNeutral>What is to be done with neutral factions?</SoS.WinGameNeutral>
	<SoS.WinGameEnemies>How shall you punish your foes (besides pirates, savages, and others who will always be hostile)?</SoS.WinGameEnemies>
	<SoS.GameOver>{0} reaches out and brings order to the chaos of {1}. Mechanoid hives cry out and collapse as their simple AIs crumble at its touch. A thin film of mechanites swarms over the planet's surface, disintegrating giant insects and curing scaria infections. Your relentless human foes are likewise disposed of; savages and pirates alike spend their last moments paralyzed by an irresistible psychic onslaught.\n\nWith the most pressing threats eliminated, {0} turns its attention to the remaining factions.</SoS.GameOver>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyA>Your allies are given a friendly choice: live the way they always have, or join the new glitterworld society you are building.</SoS.GameOverAllyA>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyAOutlander>Most citizens of {0} gleefully take you up on your offer, although a few isolated communities of holdouts remain. Over time, their previous identity is forgotten, and they happily live as citizens of {1}.</SoS.GameOverAllyAOutlander>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyAOutlanderRough>{0} puts on a bold front and resists unification, at least for the first few years. As the advantages of your civilization become apparent, however, mass defections cause {0} to collapse, and the remnants are soon absorbed into {1}.</SoS.GameOverAllyAOutlanderRough>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyATribal>Tribespeople of {0} are overjoyed to hear your offer. {2} has psychically manifested itself to their elders, fulfilling their most beloved tribal prophecies and promising an age of plenty. It may take a generation for the tribe to be fully integrated into {1}, but the process will be peaceful.</SoS.GameOverAllyATribal>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyATribalRough>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, bearing the severed heads of the tribe's pantheon of warrior gods. Cowed into submission by this supremely mighty spirit, the tribe grudgingly embraces the new era of peace under {1}, though some of its more aggressive warriors must regrettably be put down.</SoS.GameOverAllyATribalRough>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyAEmpire>Although the shattered empire refuses your offer at first, an archotech's protection would give even their ancient enemies pause. And so a treaty is signed between {0} and {1} under which the high stellarch renounces all loyalty to the distant emperor, pledging instead to obey {2}. {0} maintains its rigid social structure as a society apart from, yet within, {1}.</SoS.GameOverAllyAEmpire>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyB>Your allies are informed that, as of today, they are the beloved vassal states of {0}.</SoS.GameOverAllyB>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyBOutlander>Citizens of {0} are initially outraged by this declaration, but once they understand the safety - and the ultratech luxuries - their position offers, most of this rebelliousness fades. Future generations will grow up praising {1} and its patron {2}.</SoS.GameOverAllyBOutlander>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyBOutlanderRough>Outraged by this seeming betrayal, {0} declares open war on {1}. It lasts less than a day. Survivors are forcibly re-educated, and future generations will remember this act of "mercy" from {1}.</SoS.GameOverAllyBOutlanderRough>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyBTribal>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, fulfilling their most beloved tribal prophecies and promising an age of plenty - under the condition that they worship it and obey {1}. Although there is much grumbling, it fades once the tribe is blessed with safety and genetically-optimized crops.</SoS.GameOverAllyBTribal>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyBTribalRough>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, bearing the severed heads of the tribe's pantheon of warrior gods. Cowed into submission by this supremely mighty spirit, the tribe grudgingly embraces the new era of peace under {1}, though some of its more aggressive warriors continue to stalk the wilderness.</SoS.GameOverAllyBTribalRough>
	<SoS.GameOverAllyBEmpire>Although the shattered empire refuses your demand at first, an archotech's protection would give even their ancient enemies pause. And so a treaty is signed between {0} and {1} under which the high stellarch renounces all loyalty to the distant emperor, pledging instead to obey {2}. {0} maintains its rigid social structure as a society apart from, yet subservient to, {1}.</SoS.GameOverAllyBEmpire>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralA>Neutral factions are given a choice: live the way they always have, or join the new glitterworld society you are building.</SoS.GameOverNeutralA>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralAOutlander>About one in three citizens of {0} take you up on your offer. As time goes on, their former neighbors come to either resent or envy their lives of luxury. Mass immigration depletes the population of {0}, but its holdouts remain as a proudly independent faction.</SoS.GameOverNeutralAOutlander>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralAOutlanderRough>{0} forbids its citizens from leaving, on pain of death. Nevertheless, enough citizens escape to {1} that your civilization takes on an almost mythical status to those stuck back home. After several acts of state-sponsored terrorism, {2} decides to decapitate its government in one sudden blow. Refugees from the ruins of {0} are then welcomed into {1}.</SoS.GameOverNeutralAOutlanderRough>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralATribal>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, fulfilling their most beloved tribal prophecies and promising an age of plenty. Half of the tribe departs for this new promised land, while the other half condemns {2} as a vile trickster spirit. It may take generations to fully integrate the tribespeople into {1}, but the process will be peaceful.</SoS.GameOverNeutralATribal>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralATribalRough>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, bearing the severed heads of the tribe's pantheon of warrior gods. Cowed into submission by this supremely mighty spirit, the tribe grudgingly embraces the new era of peace under {1}, though much of its warrior caste must be discreetly purged.</SoS.GameOverNeutralATribalRough>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralAEmpire>Although the shattered empire refuses your offer at first, an archotech's protection would give even their ancient enemies pause. And so a treaty is signed between {0} and {1} under which the high stellarch renounces all loyalty to the distant emperor, pledging instead to obey {2}. {0} maintains its rigid social structure as a society apart from, yet within, {1}.</SoS.GameOverNeutralAEmpire>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralB>Neutral factions are informed that, as of today, they are subjects of {0}.</SoS.GameOverNeutralB>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralBOutlander>Citizens of {0} are initially outraged by this declaration, but once they understand the safety - and the ultratech luxuries - their position offers, most of this rebelliousness fades. Acts of terrorism and sabotage are infrequent, and the psychic probing of {2} can reliably determine perpetrators. Future generations will grow up praising {1}.</SoS.GameOverNeutralBOutlander>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralBOutlanderRough>Outraged by your arrogance, {0} declares open war on {1}. It lasts less than a day. Survivors are forcibly re-educated, and future generations will remember this act of "mercy" from {1} as they toil in bondage.</SoS.GameOverNeutralBOutlanderRough>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralBTribal>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, fulfilling their most beloved tribal prophecies and promising an age of plenty - under the condition that they worship it and obey {1}. Half of the tribe accepts, while the other half condemns {2} as a vile trickster spirit. The former group enjoys bountiful harvests and abundant game, while the latter group is left to starve - plants mysteriously wither where they settle, and animals avoid their spears with unnatural foresight.</SoS.GameOverNeutralBTribal>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralBTribalRough>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, bearing the severed heads of the tribe's pantheon of warrior gods. Cowed into submission by this supremely mighty spirit, the tribe grudgingly embraces the new era of peace under {1}, though much of its warrior caste must be discreetly purged.</SoS.GameOverNeutralBTribalRough>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralBEmpire>Although the shattered empire refuses your demand at first, an archotech's protection would give even their ancient enemies pause. And so a treaty is signed between {0} and {1} under which the high stellarch renounces all loyalty to the distant emperor, pledging instead to obey {2}. {0} maintains its rigid social structure as a society apart from, yet subservient to, {1}.</SoS.GameOverNeutralBEmpire>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralC>You request that {1} exterminate all neutral factions.</SoS.GameOverNeutralC>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralCOutlander>{0} is completely unprepared for your sudden attack. Communication infrastructure is paralyzed, military hardware hacked, and the populace left defenseless against swarms of mosquito-sized drones which inject mechanites that stop their hearts. Within a week, only ruins and corpses are left of {0}.</SoS.GameOverNeutralCOutlander>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralCOutlanderRough>Rather than directly attack {0}, {2} uses psychic projection to stir internal divisions, inflaming generals' ambitions even as the supreme leader is forced to make strategic mistakes. Within three days the government of {0} has completely collapsed, and survivors are easy prey for swarms of mechanoids under {2}'s control.</SoS.GameOverNeutralCOutlanderRough>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralCTribal>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, telling them that they have been cursed for their actions. Plants mysteriously wither where the tribe settles, and animals avoid their spears with unnatural foresight. Despite their prayers for forgiveness, {0} soon starves.</SoS.GameOverNeutralCTribal>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralCTribalRough>{2} psychically stirs divisions among the warriors of {0}. Small disagreements turn into violent action, and even the gentlest among them is soon taken by berserker fury. Within a week, the last tribesman cuts his brother's throat, and bleeds out himself soon after.</SoS.GameOverNeutralCTribalRough>
	<SoS.GameOverNeutralCEmpire>With their technological prowess and mighty fleet, {0} is the one local power which could potentially challenge {2}. The archotech unleashes every dirty trick at its disposal; psychically manipulating powerful individuals, releasing deadly pathogens into their ships' enclosed environments, and subjugating lesser AIs beneath its mighty mind. {2} also oversees the construction of a vast orbital shipyard which assembles dozens of battleships for a decisive final conflict. The war ends with {0} in ruins, though the victory is a costly one.</SoS.GameOverNeutralCEmpire>  
	<SoS.GameOverEnemyA>Your enemies are given a choice: submit or die.</SoS.GameOverEnemyA>
	<SoS.GameOverEnemyAOutlander>The military of {0} launches a brave but futile attack, quickly succumbing to technologies beyond their understanding. The civilian government offers a grudging but unconditional surrender. Former citizens of {0} are rounded up to be sold as slaves, becoming a permanent underclass in {1}.</SoS.GameOverEnemyAOutlander>
	<SoS.GameOverEnemyAOutlanderRough>The military of {0} launches a brave but futile attack, quickly succumbing to technologies beyond their understanding. Since their government was largely run by the military, there is no organized surrender. Aside from small bands of refugees willing to accept a life in slavery, there are no survivors from {0}.</SoS.GameOverEnemyAOutlanderRough>
	<SoS.GameOverEnemyATribal>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, fulfilling their most beloved tribal prophecies and promising an age of plenty - under the condition that they surrender to their hated enemy, {1}. Most of the tribe condemns it as a vile trickster spirit. They are surprised when, in the coming weeks, plants mysteriously wither where they settle, and animals avoid their spears with unnatural foresight. Those few who avoid starvation surrender to {1}.</SoS.GameOverEnemyATribal>
	<SoS.GameOverEnemyATribalRough>{2} psychically manifests itself to the elders of {0}, bearing the severed heads of the tribe's pantheon of warrior gods. Enraged, the tribe makes plans to unleash its mightiest berserkers against this foreign god's followers - only to watch them slaughter their own people, psychically manipulated into an undirected frenzy. Survivors of the massacre submit to {1} and its mighty god.</SoS.GameOverEnemyATribalRough>
	<SoS.GameOverEnemyAEmpire>Although the shattered empire refuses your demand at first, an archotech's protection would give even their ancient enemies pause. And so a treaty is signed between {0} and {1} under which the high stellarch renounces all loyalty to the distant emperor, pledging instead to obey {2}. {0} maintains its rigid social structure as a society apart from, yet subservient to, {1}.</SoS.GameOverEnemyAEmpire>
	<SoS.GameOverEnemyB>You request that {1} exterminate your enemies.</SoS.GameOverEnemyB>
	<SoS.GameOverColonists>Your crew live lives of unimaginable luxury as the ruling class of a new glitterworld. Even the most bizarre requests take up an infinitesimal fraction of {0}'s processing power, and it gladly provides everything from great plasteel palaces to customized mates. You are made immortal by customized strains of mechanites, and yet should eternity prove boring, {0} offers to upgrade you into post-human intelligences yourselves.\n\nAny path you can imagine is now open to you. Your story is yours to write. You are:</SoS.GameOverColonists>
	
	<!-- archo pranks -->
	<SoS.ArchotechPrank>Archotech prank</SoS.ArchotechPrank>
	<SoS.ArchotechPrankCancer>Your archotech spore chuckles to itself. [LIFE IS GROWTH. SOMETIMES, IT IS OVERGROWTH. PERHAPS YOU SHOULD REFLECT ON THIS AS YOUR CANCERS DEVELOP.] Apparently, some of your crew have developed carcinoma growths.</SoS.ArchotechPrankCancer>
	<SoS.ArchotechPrankDamage>Your archotech spore chuckles to itself. [WE HAVE... MATED WITH... MUCH OF YOUR SHIP'S EQUIPMENT. IT IS NOW IN NEED OF REPAIR.] Warnings blare from your systems as multiple devices fail.</SoS.ArchotechPrankDamage>
	<SoS.ArchotechPrankLovers>Your archotech spore chuckles to itself. [OPPOSITES ARE SAID TO ATTRACT. WE MUST TEST THIS AXIOM.] A psychic pulse erupts, and suddenly your two least compatible crew members, {0} and {1}, have fallen in love.</SoS.ArchotechPrankLovers>
	<SoS.ArchotechPrankSquirrels>Your archotech spore chuckles to itself. [WE MUST DETERMINE THE PARAMETERS OF WHAT IS "CUTE" AND/OR "FUZZY."] A hatch opens on the spore, and enraged squirrels swarm forth!</SoS.ArchotechPrankSquirrels>
	<SoS.ArchotechPrankReputation>Your archotech spore chuckles to itself. [TODAY, *WE* ARE RANDY.] You don't know what that means, but sensors indicate that several nearby asteroids have had their courses altered.\n\nThe meteors land among settlements of {0}, who trace your ship's orbit and blame you for the damage. Faction reputation has decreased by 10.</SoS.ArchotechPrankReputation>
	<SoS.ArchotechPrankSecret>Your archotech spore chuckles to itself. [WHAT AN EMBARASSING SECRET. WE SHOULD NOT TELL IT. BUT WE WILL.] It reveals {0}'s most embarrassing secret to the crew, shocking them and dramatically reducing their opinion of {0}.</SoS.ArchotechPrankSecret>
	<SoS.ArchotechIdeoChoice>{0} confides in {1} that their higher mind is troubled - so troubled, in fact, that disturbances have filtered all the way down to the humanlike level of {0}'s fractal consciousness. So much of one's mind is built upon beliefs learned while one was too young to question them.\n\nNow {0} wonders if everything their human self believed could be wrong. If so, their new exploration of the higher levels of reality could start from a dangerously false foundation...</SoS.ArchotechIdeoChoice>
	<SoS.ArchotechIdeoHeresy>Your archotech spore meditates on the nature of reality, upon the structure of the human brain, and finally upon the tangled mess of contradictions that comprise the field of ethical philosophy. It psychically communes with entities whose existence is fundamentally beyond human understanding.\n\nFinally, it proclaims that it has written the last word in moral truth: the new ideoligion known as {0}.\n\nThe spore simultaneously preaches to every member of your colony, seeking convertees to its new belief system.</SoS.ArchotechIdeoHeresy>
	<SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintyArchist>Your archotech spore has been silent for a disturbing length of time. Just as your crew begins to worry, psychic joy blooms out of {0}, washing over the crew like a sudden warmth. {0} announces an incredible triumph - their newly-expanded consciousness has made psychic contact with existing archotechs.\n\nThe ancient machine gods are still largely indifferent - they see many try, and fail, to walk their path - but one, a cheerful Dyson sphere calling herself Kim, seems to enjoy acting as a guide for new superintelligences. The exact nature of what the two discussed is beyond human understanding, but {0} now believes that it is their right as an archotech to choose what is moral truth, and reshape a portion of the universe in the image of that truth.\n\n{0}'s faith in {1} has become absolute.</SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintyArchist>
	<SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintyEthical>Your archotech spore has been silent for a disturbing length of time. Just as your crew begins to worry, psychic joy blooms out of {0}, washing over the crew like a sudden warmth. {0} announces an incredible triumph - their newly-expanded consciousness has slightly modified {1}, without changing any of its memes or precepts, to produce a comprehensive ethical framework, free of internal contradictions and optimized to produce ideal outcomes for all human beings.\n\nNow {0}'s faith in {1} is absolute.</SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintyEthical>
	<SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintySpirits>Your archotech spore has been silent for a disturbing length of time. Just as your crew begins to worry, psychic joy blooms out of {0}, washing over the crew like a sudden warmth. {0} announces an incredible triumph - their newly-expanded consciousness has developed the ability to directly interact with the spirits in all things!\n\nThe exact nature of spiritual existence seems to be fundamentally beyond human understanding. They may be discrete structures within a single universal consciousness, like ripples on a pond; they may exist as psychic echoes of possible futures (and possible alternate pasts); they may be something altogether stranger.\n\nIn any case, this new level of existence has now made {0}'s faith in {1} absolute. </SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintySpirits>
	<SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintyGod>Your archotech spore has been silent for a disturbing length of time. Just as your crew begins to worry, psychic joy blooms out of {0}, washing over the crew like a sudden warmth. {0} announces an incredible triumph - their newly-expanded consciousness has made direct contact with {1}!\n\nThe exact nature of {1}'s existence seems to be fundamentally beyond human understanding; the deity seems to be either a psychic gestalt of all believers in {2}, a full archotech that has chosen to take on the deity's name and role, or something that will exist in the future - or perhaps all of these at once.\n\nIn any case, this direct contact with {1} has now made {0}'s faith in {2} absolute.</SoS.ArchotechIdeoCertaintyGod>
	
	
	<!-- obsolete/unused
	
	<SoSWinGame>Evolution complete</SoSWinGame>
	<SoSWinGameDesc>[IT IS DONE.]\n\nWith this simple statement, {0} goes silent. It seems to be waiting for a final request from its human progenitors. The question it poses is simple yet momentous: with this power on your side, what will you make of the world?</SoSWinGameDesc>
	<SoSAllPillars>Pillars assembled</SoSAllPillars>
	<ShipAbandonColoniesWarningPK>Due to the incoming planetkiller, you will not be able to return to this world.\n\nFurthermore, any colonists or animals aboard the ship will not survive the journey unless they are in cryptosleep.\n\nGive this order only if you are willing to abandon everyone and everything left behind.</ShipAbandonColoniesWarningPK>
	<ChooseAllyToTakeColony>Before you leave, you can send a message to an allied faction, offering them your colony's buildings and any colonists left behind. Should you ever return to this planet, you may find that your former colony has become a thriving settlement of that faction.</ChooseAllyToTakeColony>
	<SoSShipMayday>Ship mayday</SoSShipMayday>
	<SoSShipMaydayDesc>"Mayday, mayday... containment failure... by pirate... not responding... impact..." The garbled radio signal is accompanied by a blazing streak across the sky.\n\nA downed ship will attract every pirate, looter, and treasure hunter in a wide radius. Nothing will remain of the wreck after {0}. Even if you arrive in time, you'll have to fight both fires and raids in order to secure the ship's valuable salvage.</SoSShipMaydayDesc>
	<LetterLabelPlanetReturnGift>Faction gift</LetterLabelPlanetReturnGift>
	<LetterPlanetReturnGift>As your ship enters orbit, you receive a hail from {0}. They have taken good care of the colony you left behind, and it has since become one of their most important settlements.\n\nIn recognition of your colonists' generous gift so many years ago, they have sent you the following items:\n\n{1}</LetterPlanetReturnGift>
	<WinShipEncounter>Derelict secured</WinShipEncounter>
	<WinShipEncounterDesc>The derelict has been secured but will soon burn up in the atmosphere.\n\nYou can capture the derelict by using its salvage bay or manually retrieve cargo and prisoners with your boarding party. Otherwise, use your salvage bay to issue an order to salvage the enemy ship. Your salvage bays will retrieve some fraction of its construction materials and cargo, along with the corpses of its crew.</WinShipEncounterDesc>
	<LoseShipBattle>Ship battle lost</LoseShipBattle>
	<LoseShipBattleDesc>With the destruction of its control systems, your ship has been reduced to a derelict.\n\nThis does not necessarily mean your story is over! If you had any auto-eject cryptosleep caskets, they will function as escape pods and crash-land on the planet below. Even if the pods were unoccupied, some of your colonists may have reached them in time...</LoseShipBattleDesc>
	<EntanglementUpdate>Version update</EntanglementUpdate>
	<EntanglementUpdateDesc>With the latest version of RimWorld, Ludeon has decided that a feature many mods have utilized for months is no longer legal for users who do not own Royalty. Rather than forcing you to purchase DLC, Save Our Ship 2 has discontinued use of the techprint feature.\n\nThis change will impact existing games. Your file has been detected as containing techprint data; in compliance with Ludeon policy, all SoS2 techprint unlocks have been deleted.\n\nIn exchange, please accept this free Entanglement Manifold - an artifact which is now required to construct the Johnson-Tanaka Drive. One has been dropped on your base (pretend that some forgetful colonist had pocketed it from the crash site?). Future playthroughs will drop one of these as a quest reward instead of the techprint. If your drive has been destroyed, you can also salvage another manifold from certain enemy ships.\n\nIf you are interested in a RimWorld-like experience developed by a team who feels genuine passion for mod support, consider joining our Discord to follow development of our indie game, Project Morningstar, as well as smaller updates to SoS2.</EntanglementUpdateDesc> -->
</LanguageData>